A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), Office Files of Cristina Eguizabal FA613
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), Office Files of Cristina Eguizabal
1991-2002
1963-2003
Rockefeller Archive Center
Eguizábal, Cristina
Ford Foundation
FA613
17.84 Cubic Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Subject files series material was transferred to RAC in 2018 by the Ford Foundation and ingested by RAC as Accession 2018:070.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in six series by file type:
1. Chronological Correspondence, 1995-1999
2. Program/Project Files, 1974-2002
3. Cuba Files, 1963-2003
4. Grant Files, 1990-2002
5. Consultant Files, 1996-2002
6. Subject Files, 1990-2000
Scope and Contents
Contains correspondence, program and project files, Cuba files, grant files, consultant files and subject files.
Biographical / Historical
Cristina Eguizabal served as a program officer responsible for Latin America regional grant-making in Peace and Social Justice at the Ford Foundation in New York and México City from 1995-2007. She holds a Ph.D. in Latin American Studies from the University of Paris III, Sorbonne Nouvelle.
Latin America; Ford Foundation; Cuba
- Chronological Correspondence, 1995-2002; 1; 1.69 Cubic Feet
  - 1995 Chronological Correspondence, A-Z (Box 1)
  - 1996 Chronological Correspondence, A-M (Box 1)
  - 1996 Chronological Correspondence, N-Z (Box 1)
  - 1998 Chronological Correspondence, A-L (Box 1)
  - 1998 Chronological Correspondence, M-Z (Box 1)
  - 1999 Chronological Correspondence, A-M (Box 1)
  - 1999 Chronological Correspondence, N-Z (Box 1)
  - 2000 Chronological Correspondence A-Z (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - 2001 Chronological Correspondence A-Z (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - 2002 Chronological Correspondence A-Z (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Program/Project Files, 1974-2002; 2; 6.57 Cubic Feet 5 record storage boxes
  - Acronyms of Latin America Programs, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Activity Reports -- Cristina Eguizabal, 1995-2001 (Box 2)
  - American Assembly (The) -- "The U.N. System and U.S. National Interests" Workshop, 1995 (Box 2)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science -- Memoranda and Report, "Confronting the Demand for Scientific and Scholarly Literature in Portuguese", 1992-1994 (Box 2)
  - Arts International, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Budgets -- Latin America and the Caribbean, 2002 (Box 2)
  - Caribbean Program Briefing Book, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Central America Initiative (folder 1), 1993-1996 (Box 2)
  - Central America Initiative (folder 2), 1996-1997 (Box 2)
  - Central America Initiative (folder 3), 1996 (Box 2)
  - Central America Initiative -- Background, 1995-1997 (Box 2)
  - Central America Initiative -- Grants, 1995-1997 (Box 2)
  - Central America Initiative -- Grantee Meeting, Guatemala, Oct 1997 (Box 2)
  - Central America Initiative -- Grantee Meeting -- Materials, Reports, Notes, Oct 1997 (Box 2)
  - Central America Initiative -- Grantee Meeting -- Meeting Book (1 of 2), Oct 1997 (Box 2)
  - Central America Initiative -- Grantee Meeting -- Meeting Book (2 of 2), Oct 1997 (Box 2)
  - Central America Initiative -- Xabier Gorostiaga Article, Oct 1997 (Box 2)
  - Central America Initiative -- Guatemala, 1994-1997 (Box 2)
  - Central America Initiative -- IAD/ASIES, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Central America Initiative -- Meetings (incl. preparation for Oct 5-9, 1997 meeting) (Box 2)
  - Central America Initiative -- Meeting (Sep 26, 1995) on International Aspects of Central America Initiative (Box 2)
  - Central America Initiative -- Notes, Grant Documentation, 1992-1995 (Box 2)
  - Central America Initiative -- Notes, Materials from the Mexico City Office, 1995-1997 (Box 2)
  - Central America Initiative -- Trip (1997), 1995-1997 (Box 2)
  - Central America Initiative -- Washington Meeting Prep and Materials (May 23, 1995) (Box 2)
  - Central America Issues Re: Human Rights, Ford Foundation Trips, etc., 1994 (Box 2)
  - CIRMA (Centro de Investigaciones Regionales de Mesoamerica), undated (Box 2)
  - Citizen Security, 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - Civil Military Affairs in Asia, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Civil Military Programs -- NDI, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Civil Military Relations -- HRDC, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Civil Military (Michele Dash), 1989-1996 (Box 2)
  - Civil Military, 1995-1996 (Box 2)
  - Civil Military -- Latin American Working Group (LAWG) -- Military Aid, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Civil Society Integration, 1994-1996 (Box 3)
  - Coalition for Haitian Refugees -- Grant Proposal, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Colombia and the Ford Foundation, 1999-2000 (Box 3)
  - Colombia -- LEF (Learning Enhancement Fund), 2001 (Box 3)
  - Colombia -- Correspondence with Juan Tokatlian, Materials Re: Colombia and Panama Trip, Additional Documents, 2000-2001 (Box 3)
  - Colombia -- Human Rights Committee, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Colombia -- Working Group on, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Colombia, 2000-2001 (Box 3)
  - Colombia -- WOLA (Washington Office on Latin America) Re: Andean Crisis and U.S. Drug Control, undated (Box 3)
  - CONLACTRAHO (Confederacion Latino Americaa y del Caribe de Trabajadoras del Hogar) -- Ford Foundation Grant, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Daubon, Ramon -- Re: Caribbean Integration Project, 1995-1997 (Box 3)
  - Demilitarization -- Central America, 1996-1997 (Box 3)
  - Diamint, Rut -- Re: Civil-Military Issue in Latin America, 1997 (Box 3)
  - Dominican Republic -- Ford Foundation Work, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Education and Culture -- Grant Recommendations Re: Art, Education in Africa, Asia and Latin America, 1994 (Box 3)
  - English Language -- Cristina Eguizabal's Practice, Editing Work, Work with Tutors, 1995-1996 (Box 3)
  - Ethnicity in Latin America -- "Promoting and Integrating Race/Ethnic Diversity in Brazil" by Edward E. Telles, Mar 19, 1996 (Box 3)
  - Fellowships, 1999-2001 (Box 3)
  - Ford Foundation "Report" -- Winter 1996 (Vol. 27, No. 1) (Box 3)
  - Funda Paz, 1995 (Box 3)
  - FUNPADEM, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Global Security Learning Group, 1997-1998 (Box 3)
  - Grant Administration Practices and Biennial Budget (FY 1998), 1997 (Box 3)
  - Grant List (by program) -- Education, Arts and Culture; Peace and Social Justice; International Affairs; Urban Poverty, 1996-1997 (Box 3)
  - Grantee List (by program), undated (Box 3)
  - Grantee Mailing Lists and Addresses, 1996 (Box 3)
  - Grantmaking -- List of Grants by Primary RPO, Cuba-Related Grants, and IRS Withholding Requirements Memorandum, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Haiti Contact Information, 1988-1991 (Box 3)
  - "Haiti Democratic Needs Assessment" Report, May 1989 (Box 3)
  - Haiti -- "Environment and Development in Haiti" by R. Trouillot, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Haiti -- Grants and Grantees, Trip Files, Memoranda, etc., 1988-1995 (Box 3)
  - Haiti in the United States -- Trip and Meeting Notes, Background, 1988; 1989 (Box 3)
  - Haiti Information Bureau, 1992 (Box 3)
  - Harvard University -- David Rockefeller Center for Latin American Studies -- Governance Policy and Research Seminar, Sep 11, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Harvard University Re: INVESP, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Human Rights and International Cooperation -- Memoranda and Reports, 2001 (Box 3)
  - ICT Meeting and Background Materials, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Impact Communications incl. Representative's Handbook, 1996-1998 (Box 4)
  - International Cooperation, 1998 (Box 4)
  - International Cooperation -- Brainstorming, 1999 (Box 4)
  - International Cooperation Grants in Latin America, 1974-1993 (Box 4)
  - International Development Law Institute, 1991-1994 (Box 4)
  - International Directory of Foundations, 1991 (Box 4)
  - International Organizations -- Ford Foundation Grant List, 1996 (Box 4)
  - ITAM (Instituto Tecnologico Autonomo de Mexico), 2000-2001 (Box 4)
  - INVESP (Instituto Venezolano de Estudios Sociales y Politicos), 2002 (Box 4)
  - Johns Hopkins University -- Alejandro Portes File Re: Latin American Immigration, 1995-1996 (Box 4)
  - Third Latin American Congress of Social Science and Medicine (Apr 8-12, 1995), 1994-1995 (Box 4)
  - Latin America Contacts, 1990-1991 (Box 4)
  - Latin America Human Rights Meeting, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Latin America Regional Program Budget Projections (FY 1994-1995) (Box 4)
  - Media 1994/1995 -- Activities, Strategies, Campaigns, 1993-1995 (Box 4)
  - Mexico/New York Collaboration, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Mexico City Office -- Cristina Eguizabal Application for Representative, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Migration, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Migration -- Draft Paper Re: Migration, Trade and Human Rights Advocates, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Multilateralism -- FLACSO -- Grant Proposal, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Mouvman Peyizan Papay -- Grant Recommendation, Background, 1989-1994 (Box 4)
  - Nature Conservancy (The), 1995 (Box 4)
  - NGOs (folder 1), 1995-1997 (Box 4)
  - NGOs (folder 2), 1997 (Box 4)
  - NGOs -- West Africa Rural Foundation -- Philanthropy in Africa Grant Recommendation, 1998 (Box 4)
  - NGOs -- "Strengthening Philanthropy Worldwide: A Ford Foundation Governance and Civil Society Discussion Paper" by Michael Seltzer, Dec 1997 (Box 4)
  - Organizations -- American Friends Service Committee Meeting (Philadelphia), Nov 18, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Organizations - Aspen Institute -- Cuba Meeting, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Organizations -- Columbia University (lecture?), Feb 28, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Organizations -- Cuban-American National Council, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Organizations -- Institute of Caribbean and International Studies, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Organizations -- Institute for Food and Development Policy, 1995-1996 (Box 4)
  - Organizations -- Institute for Human Rights and Responsibilities, 1998-2000 (Box 4)
  - Organizations -- Latin America Working Group, 1997-1998 (Box 4)
  - Pacific Rim -- Grant Recommendations, Proposals, Memoranda, etc., 1995 (Box 4)
  - Police Work -- Ford Foundation Grant Lists, Recommendations, 1990-1997 (Box 4)
  - Policing and Citizen Security -- Chuck Call -- Crime, Violence, Police, Public Security Issues, 1997-1998 (Box 4)
  - Policing and Citizen Security -- Violence and Police Proposals and Ford Foundation Interest, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Policing and Citizen Security -- Descriptions of Current Ford Foundation Programming on Police, Feb 1998 (Box 4)
  - Policing and Citizen Security, 1997-1998 (Box 4)
  - Population -- 1994 United Nations Population Conference, 1993-1994 (Box 5)
  - Professional Development, 1997-1999 (Box 5)
  - Program Officer's Memo (POM) and Field Statement of Current Programming, 1998-1999 (Box 5)
  - Regionalism -- with Michele Dash, 1997-1998 (Box 5)
  - Religious -- International Relations, 1999 (Box 5)
  - Reproductive Health Group, 1994-1995 (Box 5)
  - Reproductive Health -- Grant Recommendations Re: Reproductive Health Training and Research, Sex Education, Gender Studies, etc., 1993-1994 (Box 5)
  - Restructure Letter to Grantees from A. Romero, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Rural Poverty -- Grant Recommendation -- Indonesia (Social Forestry), 1992 (Box 5)
  - Rural Poverty -- Grant Recommendations -- Latin America, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Rutgers Advanced Management Course (Aug 10-14, 1998) Attended by Cristina Eguizabal (Box 5)
  - Shared Grants -- International Affairs/Latin America and the Caribbean (incl. Central America Initiative), 1995 (Box 5)
  - Social Science Research Council -- Eric Hershberg, 1993-1994 (Box 5)
  - Social Science Research Council June 1999 Meeting, Jun 1999 (Box 5)
  - Social Science Research Council September 1999 Meeting, Sep 1999 (Box 5)
  - Social Science Research Council October 1999 Meeting, Oct 1999 (Box 5)
  - Social Summit -- World Summit for Social Development, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Strengthening Peace -- Grant/Project Proposals, Meetings, etc., 1996-1997 (Box 5)
  - Transition Memorandum and Portfolio Review Memorandum Re: Latin America and the Caribbean/United States Relations and Security, 2001 (Box 5)
  - Truth Commission, 1997 (Box 5)
  - United Nations Work -- Ford Foundation Grants Relating to United Nations, 1995-1996 (Box 5)
  - United Nations University -- Regional Papers, 1996 (Box 5)
  - United Nations University -- Regional -- Latin America -- Cristina Eguizabal Paper, "Regional Arrangements, the UN and Security in Latin America" (draft), 1996 (Box 5)
  - United Nations University -- Regional -- Latin America, 1996 (Box 5)
  - United Nations University -- SINTESIS/LA Prensa -- Paper by Cristina Equizabal Re: U.S. and Latin American Relations, 1996 (Box 5)
  - United Nations University -- Latin American Foreign Policy -- Human Rights, Cristina Equizabal Paper, 1997-1999 (Box 5)
  - United Nations University -- Foreign Policy/Human Rights (folder 1), 1996-1997 (Box 5)
  - United Nations University -- Foreign Policy/Human Rights (folder 2), 1997-1998 (Box 5)
  - UTDT -- Grant Proposal, 2001 (Box 5)
  - Washington Office on Latin America (WOLA), 1991-1995 (Box 5)
  - Women and Politics, 1991-1995 (Box 5)
  - Women's Group -- Beijing Conference, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Women's Rights as Human Rights, 1987-1992 (Box 5)
  - Women's Groups in the Dominican Republic -- Elsa Chaney Report, "Women Breaking Boundaries", 1992 (Box 6)
  - Women's Program Forum, 1997 (Box 6)
  - Woodrow Wilson Center for Scholars -- Latin America's Role in the New Global System Workshop, May 25, 1998 (Box 6)
  - Worldwide Workshop for Media, Arts and Culture Programmers, Apr 1998 (Box 6)
- Cuba Files, 1963-2003; 3; 2.63 Cubic Feet 2 record storage boxes
  - Afro-Cubans, 1999 (Box 6)
  - American Assembly, 2001 (Box 6)
  - American Friends Service Committee -- Cuba Meeting, Sep 12, 1997 (Box 6)
  - AIETI (Asociacion de Investigacion y Especializacion sobre Temas Iberoamericanos), 2001 (Box 6)
  - Biographies, 1993 (Box 6)
  - CFR (Council of Foreign Relations) -- "Cuba and Religious Organizations in the Run-up to the Papal Visit" Seminar (Sep 4, 1997) (Box 6)
  - CIPAF (Centro de Investigacion Para la Accion Femenina), 1999 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence (General), 1993-1995 (Box 6)
  - CRIES -- ACS, 2002 (Box 6)
  - CSIS (Center for Strategic and International Studies) -- Cuba, 1999 (Box 6)
  - CSIS (Center for Strategic and International Studies) -- IIE, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Cuban Arts -- International Arts Foundation, Adolfo Nodal Re: "MEMORIA: Cuban Art of the 20th Century", 2002 (Box 6)
  - Cuban and Caribbean Grant Possibilities -- Immigration, Democracy, etc., 1994-1996 (Box 6)
  - Cuban Center, 1999 (Box 6)
  - Cuban Committee for Democracy -- Proposals, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Cuba in the 21st Century Conference -- U.S. State Department, 1999 (Box 6)
  - Cuba Program OPF Meeting -- Presentation Slides/Handout, undated (Box 6)
  - CIRMA (Centro de Investigaciones Regionales de Mesoamerica) -- Proposals, 2000-2001 (Box 6)
  - CIEPLAN (Corporation for Latin American Economic Research) -- Memoranda Re: Funding Possibilities, 1995-1996 (Box 6)
  - Cuba Grantee Meeting (3/25-26/1999) -- Grantee Invitation Letter (Box 6)
  - Cuba Grantee Meeting (3/25-26/1999) -- Experts Invitation Letters (Box 6)
  - Cuba Grantee Meeting (3/25-26/1999) -- Meeting Agenda, Preparation Materials, Invitation Lists, etc. (Box 6)
  - Cuba Grantee Meeting (3/25-26/1999) -- Cuban Invitation Letters (Box 6)
  - Cuba Grantee Meeting (3/25-26/1999) -- Active Cuba Grants FY 1997-1998 (Box 6)
  - Cuba Grantee Meeting (3/25-26/1999) -- Confirmations (Box 6)
  - Cuba Grantee Meeting (3/25-26/1999) -- Notes (Box 6)
  - Cuba Grantee Meeting (3/25-26/1999) -- Incl. Information on Grantees (Box 6)
  - Georgetown -- Proposal/Concept Paper, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Grants, 1990-1995 (Box 6)
  - Grant-Related, 1992-1994 (Box 6)
  - Grants -- Cuba Related, undated (Box 6)
  - Grants -- Cuba Grants List (Ford Foundation and other funders), 1998 (Box 6)
  - Grants (Ford Foundation) to Cuba between 1950 and 2001 (Box 6)
  - Grants -- Other Funders, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Grants and Memoranda Re: Ford Foundation Work in Cuba, 1963-2002 (Box 6)
  - Human Rights -- Cuba, 1997-2000 (Box 6)
  - Informal Conusltant Information, 1997-2001 (Box 6)
  - Information and Materials on Cuba -- Memoranda, Background, Event Invitation, etc., 1995-1996 (Box 6)
  - IIE (Institute of International Education) -- Global Travel Fund Contracts, 1999 (Box 6)
  - IIE (Institute of International Education) -- Global Travel -- Trip Reports, 2000 (Box 6)
  - IIE (Institute of International Education) -- Travel Funds, 1997-1998 (Box 6)
  - Lexington Institute, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Ludwig Foundation of Cuba (and its American Friends branch), 2001 (Box 6)
  - Memoranda/Email, 1992-1995 (Box 6)
  - Memoranda -- Cuba, 1995-1996 (Box 6)
  - Memoranda, Notes, Grant Lists, Recommendations for Grant Action, etc., 1997-1998 (Box 6)
  - Mesa-Lago, Carmelo -- Correspondence and Report Re: Cuba and Ford Foundation Funding, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Miami Herald Re: Published Article, 1998 (Box 7)
  - Nelson Valdes -- Cuba Research and Analysis Group, 2000-2001 (Box 7)
  - Philadelphia Group and InterAction Cuba Working Group, 1997 (Box 7)
  - Powerpoint by Cristina Eguizabal Re: Cuba, 1995 (Box 7)
  - Cuba Project -- Bildner Center Proposal, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Cuba Project -- Bildner Center, 2002-2003 (Box 7)
  - Cuba Project -- B. Alvarado, 2002 (Box 7)
  - Cuba Project -- Bob Bach/SUNY, 1984-1989 (Box 7)
  - Proposals Re: Cuba, 1992-1995 (Box 7)
  - RAND Forum on Cuba, 1999 (Box 7)
  - Reflection Memo and Workplan, 1999-2000 (Box 7)
  - Report, Notes, Grant Lists Re: Cuba and Ford Foundation Work, 1998 (Box 7)
  - Report -- "Email and the Internet in Cuba" by Cuba Research and Analysis Group, Feb 2001 (Box 7)
  - Report -- "Reform in Cuba", 1989 (Box 7)
  - Report -- Alfonso W. Quiroz Report Re: Trip to Cuba (Ford Foundation funded) and NGOs in Cuba, 2000 (Box 7)
  - SSRC -- Re: Libraries and Archives in Cuba, 2000-2001 (Box 7)
  - Task Force Meeting (Feb 22, 1993) Materials, 1992-1993 (Box 7)
  - Tocqueville Interim Report, 1997-1999 (Box 7)
  - Trip to Cuba (1/28-2/4/1996), 1995-1996 (Box 7)
  - Trip to Cuba -- Contacts, Background, etc., 1995-1996 (Box 7)
  - Trip to Cuba (1997) (Box 7)
  - Trip to Cuba (Jun 1-6, 1998) (Box 7)
  - Trip to Cuba (Jan 1999), 1998 (Box 7)
  - Trustees Updates Re: Ford Foundation Work in Cuba, 1999 (Box 7)
  - United States Association of Former Members of Congress -- Trip to Cuba Proposal, 1995 (Box 7)
  - USAID -- Cuba, 2002 (Box 7)
  - United States Embargo on Cuba -- Memorandum, 2000 (Box 7)
  - United States Embargo on Health and Nutrition in Cuba, 1998 (Box 7)
  - United States Foreign Policy -- Cuba, 1998-1999 (Box 7)
  - Women -- Cuban -- Grant Proposals, 1998-1999 (Box 7)
  - Woodrow Wilson Center -- Cuba, 2000-2001 (Box 7)
- Grant Files, 1990-2002; 4; 7.89 Cubic Feet 6 record storage boxes
  - Grant Files, Recommendations, 1990-1998 (Box 8)
    - Grantee Liaison Book, A-C, 1995-1998 (Box 8)
    - Grantee Liaison Book, C-I, 1995-1998 (Box 8)
    - Grantee Liaison Book, I-Z, 1995-1998 (Box 8)
    - Recommendation for Grant Action (RGA) Liaison File, 1993-1996 (Box 8)
    - HRIC -- FY 1997 Grants, A-G (Box 8)
    - HRIC -- FY 1997 Grants, J-O (Box 8)
    - HRIC -- FY 1997 Grants, U-Y (Box 8)
    - Communities, Livelihoods and Families -- Reproductive Health and Population -- Grant Recommendations, 1992-1996 (Box 8)
    - Communities, Livelihoods and Families -- Rural Poverty and Resources -- Grant Recommendations (1 of 2), 1992-1996 (Box 8)
    - Communities, Livelihoods and Families -- Rural Poverty and Resources -- Grant Recommendations (2 of 2), 1992-1996 (Box 8)
    - Education, Arts and Culture -- Grant Recommendations (1 of 2), 1991-1996 (Box 8)
    - Education, Arts and Culture -- Grant Recommendations (2 of 2), 1991-1996 (Box 8)
    - Governance and Public Policy (GPP) -- Grant Recommendations, 1990-1996 (Box 8)
    - Peace and Social Justice -- Book 2 -- International Affairs (1 of 3), 1992-1996 (Box 8)
    - Peace and Social Justice -- Book 2 -- International Affairs (2 of 3), 1992-1996 (Box 8)
    - Peace and Social Justice -- Book 2 -- International Affairs (3 of 3), 1992-1996 (Box 8)
    - Rights and Social Justice (RSJ) -- Grant Recommendations, 1992-1996 (Box 8)
    - Urban Poverty -- Grant Recommendations, 1993-1996 (Box 8)
  - American Friends of the Ludwig Foundation of Cuba, 2001 (Box 9)
  - Arias Foundation/Fundacion Arias (folder 1), 1994-1997 (Box 9)
  - Arias Foundation/Fundacion Arias (folder 2), 1991-1998 (Box 9)
  - Arias Foundation for Peace and Human Progress -- Grant #980-0460-1 -- Evaluation (folder 1), 1999 (Box 9)
  - Arias Foundation for Peace and Human Progress -- Grant #980-0460-1 (folder 2), 2000 (Box 9)
  - Autonomous Technological Institute of Mexico (ITAM) -- GF#1005-0406, 1999 (Box 9)
  - Autonomous Technological Institute of Mexico (ITAM) -- GF#985-1040, 1995-2000 (Box 9)
  - Caribbean Network of Art Presenters -- GF#990-1190 -- CARIBNET and Treasury License, 1999-2000 (Box 9)
  - Canadian Foundation for the Americas (FOCAL) -- GF#100000560 -- FOCAL Concept Papers and Proposals, 1999-2000 (Box 9)
  - Caribbean Cultural Center, 1999-2000 (Box 9)
  - Center for International Policy, Inc. -- GF#970-0836, 1997-2000 (Box 9)
  - Center for Public Integrity (CPI) -- GF#975-0342 (folder 1), 1996-1997 (Box 9)
  - Center for Public Integrity (CPI) -- GF#975-0342 (folder 2), 1999 (Box 9)
  - Centro de Investigaciones Regionales de Mesoamerica (CIRMA/Center for Research on the Mesoamerica Region) -- GF#980-0527 (folder 1), 1997-1998 (Box 9)
  - Centro de Investigaciones Regionales de Mesoamerica (CIRMA/Center for Research on the Mesoamerica Region) -- GF#980-0527 (folder 2), 1999-2000 (Box 9)
  - City University of New York (CUNY) -- GF#970-0838 -- Cuba (folder 1), 1996-1997 (Box 9)
  - City University of New York (CUNY) -- GF#970-0838 -- Falk (folder 2), 1998 (Box 9)
  - City University of New York (CUNY) -- GF#970-0838 -- Cuba (folder 3), 1998-2001 (Box 9)
  - Coordinatora Regional de Investigaciones Economicas y Sociales (CRIES/Regional Coordinator of Economic and Social Research) -- GF#990-1391 -- Cuba and Citizen Security, 1998-2000 (Box 9)
  - Council on Foreign Relations -- GF#1000-0837 -- Latin America -- Cuba, 1999-2000 (Box 9)
  - Council on Foreign Relations -- GF#1000-0837 -- Caritas, 1999-2000 (Box 9)
  - Cuban Committee for Democracy (CCD) -- GF#980-1100; 970-0839 (folder 1), 1996 (Box 9)
  - Cuban Committee for Democracy (CCD) -- GF#980-1100; 970-0839 (folder 2), 1998-1999 (Box 9)
  - Cuban Committee for Democracy (CCD) -- GF#980-1100; 970-0839 (folder 3) -- Evaluation, 1998-2000 (Box 9)
  - DataCenter -- GF#980-0297, 1996-1997 (Box 9)
  - East-West Center -- GF#980-0461 -- Narrative/Financial Reports, 1999-2000 (Box 9)
  - Encuentro de la Cultura Cubana -- GR#990-1023 (folder 1), 1999 (Box 10)
  - Encuentro de la Cultura Cubana -- GR#990-1023 (folder 2), 2000-2001 (Box 10)
  - Facultad Latinoamericana de Ciencias Sociales (FLACSO) - Chile, Dominican Republic, Costa Rica (Latin American Faculty of Social Sciences) -- GF#980-0340; 980-0281 -- CR, Cuba (folder 1), 1995 (Box 10)
  - Facultad Latinoamericana de Ciencias Sociales (FLACSO) - Chile, Dominican Republic, Costa Rica (Latin American Faculty of Social Sciences) -- GF#980-0340; 980-0281 -- Cuba -- Evaluation (folder 2), 1999 (Box 10)
  - Facultad Latinoamericana de Ciencias Sociales (FLACSO) - Chile, Dominican Republic, Costa Rica (Latin American Faculty of Social Sciences) -- GF#980-0340; 980-0281 -- DR Fiscal Year 1998 (folder 3), 1996-1997 (Box 10)